CARLA JENSEN

Machine Learning Engineer

Ferney, SD

SUMMARY

ML Engineer and Team Leader with 12+ years of experience in managing machine learning lifecycles end-to-end in manufacturing and healthcare. Currently, overseeing the work of 3 ML and AI professionals to constantly find ground for improvement. Apt at developing, building, and maintaining both ETL and ML pipelines to increase data accuracy and predictability by a 45% AVG. Perfectionist, always open to collaborate with data science and industry professionals to look outside current frameworks and discover 1k+ more working solutions for each individual problem.

EXPERIENCE

Machine Learning Engineer and Team Leader

SMART Technologies

Company, specializing in AI and ML solutions for manufacturing and production.

- · Managing the whole ML lifecycle: from end-to-end deployment to constantly updating the systems to reflect new technological innovations and research, provided by 16 nation-wide institutions
- Created 15+ ETL pipeline (to train datasets) and 20+ ML pipelines with PyTorch, ski-kit-learn, and Numpy (training, assessing, and deploying models)
- Overseeing the work of 3 ML and AI professionals in continuous integrations, testing, deployment on the cloud (Azure Data Factory and ML Pipeline), and release methodologies to achieve 65% more accuracy

Machine Learning Engineer

Al and Robotics Ventures

= 2018 - 2021

Pittsburgh, PA

Technologies of tomorrow: innovating healthcare solutions across the globe.

- End-to-end deployment of 5 applications: building ML pipelines from scratch (with Python and various learning algorithms) and deploying on the cloud
- Constantly improving the program's efficiency by analyzing individual functions with the help of 3 data engineers
- Uplifted a machine learning project's predictive model precision by 10%
- Testing and experimenting on the platform (running models in parallel and A/B test) to reduce data segmentation and analysis delays by a 13% AVG

ML Researcher: NLP and Speech Recognition

Carnegie Mellon University

= 2016 - 2018

Pittsburgh, PA

PhD degree focused in exploring practices improving 5 applications.

- Improved data mining and automation by 45% using a scalable classifier by integrating predictive models and supervised and unsupervised learning algorithms
- Deployed the program across the cloud to meet 100% of all deadlines and follow the highest standard of security measures
- Collaborate with 10+ data engineers to improve the predictability model of data with a focus on patterns and trends

SKILLS

End-to-end deployment Deep Learning		
Automation	Algorithms	s Statistics
Python C+	++ R Jā	avaScript
Innovations	APIs Le	eadership

PROJECTS

"Where Should I Eat-Out" Chatbot

This side-project is a friendly chatbot that makes restaurant recommendations.

• Developed own API model, so that the robot successfully analyzes the emotions using APIs -"Where Should I Eat-Out" has answered 100K+ user queries in the past 6 months

Preprocessing CLI For Healthcare Data Processing

= 2020 - 2021

Pittsburgh, PA

Built simple CLI tool to meet the department's needs and save time in data preprocessing.

• The tool was able to convert 10K+ datasets to be 65% more understandable by the algorithm, using Python, OOPS, Panda, and exception handling

EDUCATION

Ph.D. in Machine Learning

Carnegie Mellon University

Master of Science in Applied Data Science

University of San Diego

Bachelor of Science in Applied Computer Science

University of Nebraska Kearney